"This film was named by
the Council of Ministers of
the Department of Entertainment...
...as being a 'Film of National
Cultural Interest'."
YOU LAUGH
First Story:
"FELICE"
Second Story:
"TWO ABDUCTIONS"
His name is "Felice".
"Happy" in name,
unhappy in fact.
Unhappy ever since, as a
young, up and coming baritone
...a heart condition forced
him to step down from the stage.
He still worked in the theatre,
but as an accountant.
Unhappy, too,
was Marika.
She had admired him
in the Sofia Theatre.
She'd followed him,
and, eventually, married him.
She now lives with a husband
who's no longer a baritone
...beneath a sky that's
no longer her own.
You're laughing.
- Just now?
- Just now.
Listen...
are you sure, Marika?
My stomach was just
making noises.
Yeah, that's it.
Listen!
It was something like that,
and you thought I was laughing.
No, you were laughing.
You want to know how? Like this:
Like that?
Why were you laughing?
I don't know.
- I know why.
- Yeah?
You only laugh like that
when you're making love.
- Who were you making love to
tonight?
I wasn't dreaming.
I never dream.
I'd like to crack that knot
of yours open and see inside.
What do you think I have
in my head, in this...
"knot" like you call it?
I'm nothing anymore.
What if I were to kiss you...
like this...
You're not jealous.
You hate me.
Where are you going now?
You should take your drops.
You're fussing over your
hair in the middle of the night,
while I'm over here going crazy.
You are going crazy.
At the bottom of the sea...
- Viva!
- Thank you!
- Such an honour!
Now here comes my niece!
Here comes my niece,
I must present myself.
- Viva!
- Thank you!
Here comes my niece,
I must present myself.
Felice! You look tired.
What are you doing at night?
You're not sleeping?
I don't sleep.
You don't do shit.
- You two are moving like tortoises.
- Morning, Sir.
Tespini, what nerve.
No, not again...
Again, this morning.
I'm sorry. Excuse me.
- The cane.
- I don't have it...
- That guy's got it.
- The cane.
- Give it to me.
Please excuse these two klutzes.
What are you laughing about?
I'll kill him.
One of these days,
At least I've got you to
make me laugh.
I don't really feel like
it this morning.
Tobia...
It happened again, last night.
You were laughing, again?
If you want to dance, Mr Conde...
I shall play the guitar...
Yes, I shall play the guitar.
Yes, I shall play it.
I shall play it.
You're sleeping.
Are you dreaming?
How much sleep did you
get last night?
"Fa" natural,
it's not a sharp.
"Fa" natural.
Shut those doors.
Yes, I shall play the guitar.
Yes, I shall play it.
I shall play it.
No.
That's a bit too bright.
Figaro seems happy,
but he's not.
He wants to go to bed with
that woman.
That "Fa" natural...
...it's almost sinister,
a challenge.
He wants revenge.
Excuse me.
This is weird. I'm singing
the way you told me to, yesterday.
You were there, too, right?
"Ironic, lively!"
And today, you want the opposite.
Explain this to me.
No, I know.
Sometimes Mozart is clear to me.
Sometimes, he's incomprehensible.
It's white, but if you
read between the notes...
...it's black, it's green.
If you're still making sense of it,
I'll come back tomorrow.
I'm searching for truth.
And you must help me find her.
- Is this an open rehearsal?
- Who's there?
It was me. Excuse me.
- "Me"? Who's "me"?
- One of our musicians?
Are you one of our musicians?
Answer me.
- No.
- Are you a singer?
No.
I'm an accountant for the theatre.
Tespini, we each have our job to do.
Go back to your office.
Back to your office.
If you want to dance, Mr Conde...
I shall play the guitar.
It's just a bit of bronchitis.
But you're not a rock, you know.
Cover yourself up when it rains.
You seem rather tense.
Are you sleeping well at night?
That's actually why I'm here,
not the bronchitis.
Insomnia?
Let me explain...
Excuse me, but when you were
in medical school...
...did you also study psychiatry?
It was as an elective,
but yes, I did. Why?
Good grades?
The only class I passed with
distinction. I had a knack.
But, here I am.
But in life, it's one thing to
aspire to something...
...and another to do it.
But you know what I mean,
don't you, Felice?
Of course.
I'm the most unfortunate
of baritones...
...the most unhappy husband,
the worst employee...
...and I laugh through the night.
Tell me, doctor, am I crazy?
You laugh?
In what way?
- Doctor, may I come in?
- Just a moment, please be patient.
So, you laugh.
I laugh.
I laugh! Like this!
A big, long, cheerful laugh!
That's what they tell me.
Doctor, is it possible to laugh
in your sleep without knowing it?
There are various methods
for interpreting dreams.
No, I don't dream.
I never dream.
That's what you think,
but you do dream.
You don't remember them
because they weigh on you.
Like dark, black lead?
But you dream.
So, I laugh at the dreams
that I'm having.
Yes, they're pleasant dreams.
Maybe you have them often.
And that's why you laugh.
I don't have any happiness in my life.
I have nothing to laugh at.
Be patient!
Just a moment!
It's a compensation.
Nature comes to your
aid in dreams.
In dreams, you're freed from
your miseries, your agonies...
...and carried lightly, like a
feather...
...through happy and pleasant
dreams.
How do you like that?
I've turned evil.
My wife is sure of it.
Because you are clearly,
fundamentally good.
If you can't be good during the day,
you are at night, when you dream...
...and laugh.
What a shame!
To be happy in dreams,
without knowing it.
Felice, come and see this.
It was raining earlier.
But look at it now!
You don't sleep in this bed
anymore. You're not going to
share it with your women!
It's not like that!
The doctor explained everything.
I dream of innocent things.
The doctor knows nothing!
Listen, Marika. Wait!
I want you to suffer
as much as I do.
Speak Italian!
I hate Italy! I hate the doctor!
And I hate your whores!
How many of them were
you with tonight?
- Have you gone crazy?
- Because I understand what you're saying?
- No. And you don't understand me!
- [RUSSIAN]
- [PROBABLY RUSSIAN]
I'm the one who's going to
go sleep somewhere else.
If you do exist, may you
be good to the good.
I beg of you, give me that
dream that makes me so happy.
But I was dreaming...
Watch out!
Curses!
I'm a klutz.
- Would you excuse me?
- Me, excuse you?
You may be a klutz,
but I'm cursed.
Don't say that over a
couple of bruises.
I just betrayed my
best friend.
Want to know how?
Do you?
No, it doesn't matter.
- I don't want to know.
- I'll tell you. I'll tell you.
I don't want to know.
Have a nice day.
Marika!
Marika, are you in the kitchen?
I hear you.
I'm here.
I need to talk to you.
In Italian, calmly.
In Italian.
You were right.
It turns out I am evil,
and my doctor's an ass.
I remembered one
of my dreams.
You don't need to be jealous.
It wasn't what you thought.
It's worse.
Marika.
Marika?
"I went back home. I went
back to Velingrad."
Now that I've made up my mind,
I'm not angry anymore.
But don't follow me.
Don't pursue me.
We had some happy times,
many years ago.
Good morning!
Have you seen Felice?
This morning?
No, no, it doesn't matter.
Today you've got every right.
What do you mean "today"?
We knew it.
I knew it.
What did you know?
Did she write you a letter, too?
Bad news travels, Felice.
Besides, I almost saw it
coming. Didn't you?
No.
And I'd rather not talk about it.
Bring me a glass of rum? Thanks.
My friend, what are you
talking about?
I'd like to believe in
fate, like our parents...
...would say, but he just
wanted to disappear for good.
Who's this?
I say that, but I don't
want to disrespect him.
-Tobia. Tobia Rambaldi.
-Tobia, what?
-Tobia...
Forgive me...
Every time I speak of
the dead...
...it makes me laugh.
Don't take so many
sleeping pills.
Don't shut the windows so tightly.
If he'd only had a woman, or something...
He was so alone.
Trust me. He killed himself.
Gracias,
soy su hermana.
My daughters, Tobia's nieces.
Mom, the coffee's ready.
You need to have something
in your stomach.
We must go on.
- And you?
- I already had some.
Forgive me.
I understand if
you don't forgive me.
Do you want me to leave?
You had the courage to say
"enough!"
Marika left too.
And I'm left alone.
Tobia,
what are you doing now?
He's... alive!
He's alive!
It's the belly.
"Digestia mortis".
It always happens
with the dead.
Especially on a hot day.
Not to me!
It won't happen to me!
Here, take this.
- Me?
- Tobia was happy.
Goodbye, Rambaldi.
See you soon, Tobia.
Very soon.
It's the last day
I'm coming to the office.
I'm leaving too, but on a
longer trip that yours.
Dear Marika, do not follow me.
Not by any means.
I hope that, wherever you are...
...you may once again live
with a man who makes you smile.
Farewell, Marika,...
...because that noctural
laughter frightens me too.
At this moment I feel a
great desire to see the ocean.
Tomorrow, I will take a
long bath...
...a very long bath.
Tobia, sitting before me...
...you told me that it's
a good idea.
Poor Rambaldi!
- We'll end up crying.
- I couldn't sleep last night.
He was such a meticulous
accountant.
But as a man, you have to
admit, he was an imbecile.
- How could you say that?
- I say it because the dead
don't scare me.
He was an imbecile.
Think about it.
When someone doesn't know what
to do with their own life...
...and then decides to throw
it away, before doing it...
The pleasures that I would
have had first!
Is there a man than I hate?
I'd kill him first, and then myself.
That's how you do it.
But he lacked courage.
Who would Tobia have killed?
Me, for example.
He hated me.
And I didn't like him either.
And not because of
his disability.
How many times had he looked at me,
wishing he could kill me!
Why didn't he do it?
Poor Rambaldi, his death
was no use to anybody.
He died an imbecile.
- I live near here.
- We'll take you.
I'd rather walk a little.
- Goodnight, Leonora.
- Goodnight, Gino.
Who's there?
Tespini! Is that you?
Did you know that you almost scared me?
Did you come to tell me something?
Yes. Something very serious.
Serious?
- Tomorrow, in the office.
- No, here, in your house.
What do you want to tell me,
at this hour of the night?
Does you know what you're doing?
Sit down!
No, I prefer to stand.
Tespini!
Is it loaded?
It's loaded.
Keep it in your pocket.
You were always very nervous.
Sit down.
Yes, I'll sit.
I'm sitting.
Now since...
...I've decided to reunite
with Tobia Rambaldi,...
- What do you mean?
- I mean that...
...in a few hours,
by morning...
...I'm going to kill myself.
And I have to watch?
There are certain things
I won't permit you to say.
Permit me.
Because before killing myself,
I'm going to kill you.
I'm going to avenge an imbecile.
Tobia.
Rambaldi,
You heard me on the stairs.
It was a joke.
I was joking!
How stupid I was!
Now I understand.
You've shown me that.
...to prove to me that
you have courage...
...and to scare someone
like me.
Bravo.
You almost succeeded...
...theatrical animal that you are.
- Bass, right?
- Baritone.
Applause.
You'd better put those hands
together to pray.
Stop! Stop!
Shut the door!
Shut it!
- You're crazy.
- Crazy? Do I seem crazy to you?
Shut the other one, too.
Now you call me crazy, but
didn't you say that Rambaldi was
...an imbecile for not killing
you before killing himself?
People like you are either
demented or imbeciles.
Shut the other door too!
Tomorrow, when people learn
of my suicide, I don't want...
...you calling me an imbecile too.
I must kill you!
Tobia, lend me a hand.
No, it's fine.
I'm not running away.
I just want to have a
glass of water.
On your knees.
Okay.
I beg you...
...not to do this.
Calm down.
I'm not going to kill you.
I don't believe that I'd
be an imbecile not to kill you.
- Can I get up?
- No.
If you knew how distant
you look to me...
...you look so tiny to me,
cute, even.
A poor little man,
with muscular legs.
- Get up, sit down, and write.
- Really?
What do I write?
"I, Gino Migliori...
confess and repent...
I repent of having called
Tobia Rambaldi an imbecile...
...for not having given himself
the pleasure of killing me...
...his enemy, the one
who's writing this, before
committing suicide.
- I write that?
- Yes.
- "Felice Tespini..."
- Yes?
"...before he killed himself...
...came to visit me...
...and told me that in order
to avoid being called an imbecile...
...he had to kill me...
He could have done it, but
he didn't...
...because he showed mercy
towards my cowardice.
It was enough for him
to declare...
...that the real imbecile
was me...
...Gino Migliori."
Now sign it.
What's the point of all this...
...if you're still decided
on killing yourself?
What's the point?
They will find it tomorrow,
on the beach, in my pocket.
Console yourself by reflecting
that mine...
...will be a little more
difficult than yours.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
Come here!
Take it, it's a toy.
Here, I'll give you the
cartridges too.
Go! Go!
- What's going on?
- Excuse me, are you free?
- Yeah, I'm free.
- Take me to the sea.
The sea's a big place. Where to?
Wherever's closest.
And hurry.
- This isn't a hearse.
- I know.
- Take me away.
- Okay.
Adieu, Tosca.
Adieu...
Hey buddy, pick me up?
Come pick me up, eh?
Sure, come here.
Come with me.
Climb aboard. We'll throw
ourselves into the sea, together.
A hearse-load of desperate men.
Climb aboard!
Joy! Joy!
Life is beautiful!
And we should not spoil
it with our presence.
Joy!
The great Felice! Is it you?
Is it really you?
Have I changed that much?
Don't you recognize me?
From the choir?
- I was just a girl.
- Nora?
- Yes!
Yes, Nora!
You mysterious man!
What are you doing here?
Just a little errand. And you?
I'm singing!
I'm pretty good now.
We're having a practice session,
out in the fresh air. Right over there!
It's not the Verona Arena,
but the company makes it work.
Come on over, I'm sure you
must know some of them.
Tell me, you with the pale eyes,
lips, and nose...
...as bad as you may feel,
I'll whisk you away.
If you have a migraine...
...I'll cure you.
I'll cure you of everything.
Nora, my errand is important.
Not to me.
We have two hours to enjoy
the sea by ourselves.
Take my bag.
You want to go swimming?
I'll get one for you, too.
I was planning on going
for a swim myself.
Are you ready?
I'm waiting.
One more hour.
It's so cold!
It feels like October.
Are you cold, too?
Felice!
Soon...
Were you not feeling well?
Or were you just holding your breath?
Holding my breath.
It's a childish thing,
but I don't believe you.
The water's too cold for that.
It's my fault,
let me make it right.
It's on me.
I should go.
She's a very good
singer now, eh?
Cheers!
- Bravo!
- You're finally smiling!
I hadn't laughed in such
a long time. Not in the daytime.
Thanks to that crazy Rossini!
Meow!
You want to come with me?
I'm headed back to Rome at 7:00.
Do you want to come?
I'll give you a lift.
Don't try to take him with you.
You're going to be busy later
with that errand you mentioned.
That's why I'm here.
- You can't put it off?
- No, I can't.
And now I'm going. I ate, I drank,
I heard you, Nora. Thank you.
I'm going.
Remember "L'Italiana in Algeri"?
The finale of the second act?
You were magnificent.
Three minutes of applause.
No, four.
You'd seduced everybody.
Including you?
Yes.
I never told you that I
was in love with you?
No. You never told me.
You never told me.
What a shame.
Who knew?
Why don't you sing?
In your deep voice?
It couldn't hurt!
No.
This headdress is such a
weight to bear...
...and I am so entangled
in these robes.
Who speaks to you...
Sorry, sorry...
This headdress weighs so
heavily on my head...
...and I am so entangled
in these robes.
He who tells you
of this party...
...does not merit
your attention.
I thank you, my lord...
...for the honour you do me.
I thank you, my lord,
for the honour that you do me.
What are they doing?
What do they want?
Pity me.
Listen to me.
I am possessed.
We have to think, here.
If I flee...
...I shall be hung.
And if I submit...
...then it's my duty to
bring him the candlestick.
Taddeo, what child is this?
You will be punished, Taddeo.
What should I do?
Calm down, gentlemen.
I'm staying.
I do not wish to displease you.
Calm down, gentlemen!
I'm staying!
I do not wish to displease you.
Calm down! I'm staying.
Such reverence!
Such an honour!
Thank you, my dear gentlemen!
Do not trouble yourselves.
I'll do everything I can.
But I can't do anything more.
Here comes my niece.
I must present myself.
Taddeo...
It would have been better...
...if you had sunk...
...to the bottom of the sea.
- Viva!
- Thank you!
- Such an honour!
Here comes my niece.
I must present myself.
Present! Present! Present!
Is that for me?
- Your uncle is calling your friend.
- Giulio!
- He asked for me?
- At school, they draw with a...
...computer like this one.
You were the best at drawing...
...and you're going to keep on
being the best.
What's this?
They told me that this diskette
explains everything.
Ah, cool.
- You're happy, eh?
- Yep.
Tell your dad.
Yes, of course.
Vincenzo, do you think I'll
win the dance contest?
Another night without dinner!
Follow the lines of Giotto's
drawing with the pencil.
Then remove it, and obtain the
graphical copy.
Later...
Why do they teach you to
draw trees like that?
I like drawing people more, too.
Look at this.
They're strangers too.
The professor was right.
He says that if you copy them
well enough...
...then you end up really
knowing these men.
All the lines in the drawing
converge at the centre...
...where the betrayal takes
place. Come closer.
Compare the face of Christ to
that of Judas...
...the traitor.
My father isn't a traitor.
He isn't Judas.
SEBASTlANO CANGEMI:
ANOTHER CONFESSION?
NO NEWS OF HIS SON'S
WHEREABOUTS
Stop!
- Go left.
- You want me to drive through
the city?
Could you take a left?
We'll move into a nice hotel.
Just the two of us.
Your uncle wants you to
get a change of scenery.
I've got a wonderful surprise
planned for you.
Vincenzo...
You see that?
Look, it's your sisters!
Mommy!
Be brave!
Is this the appreciation I
get for surprising you?
I showed you them so that
you could see that they're fine!
Everything's fine!
Speed up!
This is for us.
- All of it?
- You can choose whichever ones you want.
- That one, or that one, or that one...
- What if I want to use all of them?
Bon appetit!
How many do you want?
- How many?
- Two!
Goodnight, Rocco!
Not with bare feet I can't!
Come on, today we're playing
against Brazil!
This is how Pelé got started,
when he was a boy. Let's play!
- I play better with shoes!
- Shoes come later!
You need to feel the ball
with your skin, that's how...
...it gets in your blood.
Now pay attention! The ball!
Let's go!
Go away!
Well I didn't have fun, either.
We've got to have patience,
the two of us.
It's just a matter of days.
Don't you trust your dad?
Him, you, and me...
aren't we all a big family?
Let's get back to playing.
Without the 500 Liras, it doesn't work.
Thanks.
Look.
Come on, look. You know what
that mountain is called?
Ballaró.
You know who Ballaró was?
An abductee, like you.
It bears his name, because
he stayed on that mountain.
He never went back home.
But you...
...you're at a great hotel.
You're an artist.
I already told you.
By summer, you and your
sister will be in Cefalú,...
...cheering me on in a discotheque!
- He never went back home?
- Never.
You should know your history.
I don't want to hear it.
Let's play.
Yes, with shoes.
With shoes!
Let's go! Get the ball!
Throw it!
Let's go!
ONE HUNDRED YEARS AGO...
Doctor Ballaró!
Doctor Ballaró.
On your knees.
Are you trying to abduct me?
- No screaming.
- Jesus Christ, a trap!
- Don't blaspheme!
- Now we're in mortal danger!
- They're watching us!
Damn it!
I'm not moving from this spot.
I am not moving from this spot!
I can't do any more. I'm sick.
I'm not moving from this spot.
- Now be good, and write.
- How much do you want?
- A thousand, at least.
- More! More!
- More, of course.
But I don't have any cash.
They'll have to sell their
land, their houses.
If I say here,
what will do you?
They'll borrow it.
- Who will?
- Your mother and your sisters.
My second wife, you mean.
The sisters are hers, not mine.
You messed up, boys.
You messed up.
- You messed up. You got it wrong,
my dear Mannuzzo.
- You recognized me?
My boy...
...you cover your face and
leave your hands uncovered...
...hands that I treated, myself.
Take off that handkerchief,
Mannuzzo.
Look me in the eye.
But how?
How could you do this to me?
Enough talk.
Behave yourself, or we kill you.
You want me to behave?
You're the ones who should be
behaving yourselves!
Come one, what am I supposed
to be writing with?
- A pencil.
- You have one.
- This isn't a pencil...
- Yes, it's a pencil.
You guys don't even know
how to use a pencil.
- What do you mean?
- I mean it needs to have a point!
- Can you sharpen it?
- Yes.
Like this, with the knife.
Sharpening it... with the knife.
No knife!
Behave yourself!
If you want me to write,
I'll write. But it won't matter.
My wife and her sisters
won't respond.
They'll just say they didn't
receive any letter. And... goodbye!
They'd rather I die.
They'd never have killed me.
They were waiting for a miracle
from God...
...sooner or later...
...and that miracle's what
you boys are delivering.
Just send me home. It's
the only solution.
I'll bring you the money.
I know what you're thinking.
"This guy's going to turn us
in, as soon as he gets free."
But really, why should I spend
the little time I have...
...looking over my shoulder
for your avenging relatives?
Rotten wood.
It's shit.
Kill me here.
Kill me here,
with my eyes open.
Don't kill me in my sleep,
that's cowardly.
You don't have any
other options.
Doctor, get inside, or I'll
shoot you.
Fillicó.
You're Fillicó?
I'm lost.
I know you, you're a good man.
A beast of burden. A man of integrity.
A man of few words.
How were they able to
strip you of your decency?
How?
Get in, or I'll shoot you.
As sure as the stars in the sky,
I'll shoot you.
Where are these stars you see?
You're a beast.
Beast!
You know nothing...
...and you want to speak of
stars? What stars do you see?
You see them, you think that
they're still there?
You think they haven't
disappeared millions of years ago?
They're dead.
Dead!
If you know nothing about
the things that you see...
...then with what right do
you keep me here?
Let me go.
I came here, sir...
...to tell you that these
three boys of mine...
...have made a mistake,
and repent of their errors.
But they can't let you go.
Nor can they kill you.
They will keep you here,
until God wills it otherwise.
He shall forgive us.
Great sacrifices are in store for you.
And for them as well.
They have resigned themselves
to the punishment they have earned.
Every day, they will bring you
bread and something you eat.
One by one, they will stand
guard over you.
And the other two will work for him.
I brought you this wool coat,
for when it gets cold...
...and this lamp, for when
it gets dark.
The Fontevalle Tabernacle has two.
Up here, we are all Christs
on the cross.
I have to shit!
And I have shit here, on my
feet, like an animal?
Remove his chain.
Let's go.
Come outside.
Come on, get out.
In front of you all?
Make yourself comfortable,
we'll turn around.
I don't know if you were joking
the other night...
...when I said that the stars
are both there and not there...
...and that the eyes see
things that aren't there.
They're not there anymore, Fillicó.
I wasn't joking.
In order to reach us,
the light from those stars...
...has to travel millions
of kilometers...
...over millions of years.
By the time their light has
reached us, the stars themselves
have disappeared from the universe.
- That's how it is, Fillicó.
- What?
Light runs, like a horse?
At millions of kilometers a second.
You're joking.
I wasn't joking then,
and I'm not joking now.
You played a joke on Fillicó.
Light doesn't travel.
It's easy to play a joke on him.
He'll believe anything.
The moon, the stars,
the Milky Way, the scorpions.
They're all witchcraft.
I'm like Saint Thomas.
I only believe in what I touch...
...and in what I see.
Come here.
Your eyes...
...what do they see over there?
- The mountain, and the sky.
- What colour are they?
White.
And now what do you see?
- The sky is green.
- Green.
- And now?
- Red, like Hell.
Red, like Hell.
Your eyes, and mine...
...are like a glass through
which we observe things.
If their colours change, then
so do the things we see.
Think about that.
Things are not they way you're
used to seeing them...
...but also the way you
want to see them, Mannuzzo.
Think about that.
Only animals like you
are ignorant that the earth...
...spins like a top.
Around and around.
Do you mean that, right now...
...there are men standing upside
down, who don't fall into the sky?
- Yes, sir.
- That's incredible!
I don't believe it.
Believe it, my boy.
You are glass...
...glass that God has not yet blown.
Why don't you try to blow me?
Stand over there.
You are this...
...and this is the Earth.
Understand?
The world spins quickly, like so.
Around and around.
- And you don't fall out.
- Doctor, are you trying to kill me?
That's what Galileo said!
Galileo!
Spinning around...
...and around.
A loaf of bread.
Is this your little boy?
What's his name?
Galileo.
Galileo?
- How many children does Mannuzzo have?
- Three.
- Three. And Chicché?
- Five.
Poor Chicché!
Bring them to see me!
I'd like to get to know them,
one of these Sundays.
If I last long enough.
- What happened?
- He's been like this all day.
Leave him. Dr. Ballaró
is a good Christian...
...but a difficult man
to understand.
- It had to be red.
- What?
- The handkerchief.
- Red? Why?
- You're an animal.
- You put it on.
Right, when we kidnapped him...
...it was red.
The kids want to play.
Let's go! Let's go!
SEBASTIANO CANGEMI SPEAKS
VINCENZO'S FATHER
COLLABORATES WITH THE JUSTICE DEPT.
Right.
Left.
YOU LAUGH
Subtitles translated by
Lucca Fraser, and maintained at
http://github.com/oblivia-simplex/subtitles